<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on </title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 20:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What drives the evolution of dorsal coloration in tropidurid lizards?</title>
      <link>/project/color/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/color/</guid>
      <description>Whether the color of an animal plays a significant role in thermoregulation has been a persistent question in studies of thermal biology of ectotherms. This research project is based on the synthesis of the color-mediated thermoregulation hypothesis which states that dark individuals (i.e. lower skin reflectance) are at an advantage under conditions of low temperature since they warm up faster than light individuals at a given level of solar radiation. Although skin color is an important trait in the thermal biology of ectotherms, it has been explored mostly in insects and some reptiles of temperate zones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master&#39;s thesis</title>
      <link>/project/masters-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 18:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/masters-project/</guid>
      <description>Theoretical models predict that lizards after meal consumption must maintain high and constant body temperatures by making behavioral adjustments. Still, behavioral thermoregulation can be affected by other physiological factors such as the hydration state, body condition or can conflict with the locomotor activity of animals. Hence, the thermoregulatory behavior of a lizard should be the result of interactions among all these physiological and ecological processes. In this study we aimed to investigate the role of food intake and the hydration state on behavioral thermoregulation and locomotor activity in the tropidurid lizard Tropidurus catalanensis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>